前情提要
Previously on Lost Girl...
等我们出去之后
When we do get out of here
是时候训练你当火影神偷了
I think it's time I start training you to be a shadow thief.
Dyson没犯谋杀罪
Dyson is not guilty of murder.
是你犯的
You are.
血圣
Blood King.
可你消失了，大家都以为你死了
But you disappeared.Many think you're dead.
我希望这样最好
I'd like to keep it that way.
他是血圣，是我的亲外公
He is the Blood King.He is my grandfather.
为啥他不帮我想想我怎么会被抓
Why hasn't he helped me figure out why I was taken?
不要这么说 他不知道你胸口的记号
It's not fair. He doesn't know about the mark on your chest.
她比我们期待的要强
She is more than we expected.
嘿，医生，你觉得那个……
Hey doc, what you do you think about the uh...
哇
Whoa.
我们要帮她吗
Should we help
不用
No.
这对我们比较好，我是说，对她
It's good for us...I mean her.
我是说这是很好的治疗
I mean,I think it's therapeutic.
算上这次已经失败多少次了？
How many failed missions does this make?
她真的很想要那个Hel鞋嘛
Girl really wants that hel shoe.
拜拜了，劣等异种的肠子
Goodbye,UnderFae guts.
啤酒我来啦
Hello brewskies.
嘿，我该把油钱给谁啊
Hey, who do we pay for the gas?
就放柜台吧 ，我们信得过你
Leave the money on the counter.We trust ya.
我觉得今夜一定很棒
I got a good feeling about tonight.
我也是
Me too.
恩哼
Hmph.
*古德国地区节日，与奥丁等神关系密切，至今北欧地区仍庆祝该节日*
*本剧中相当于异种的圣诞节*
尤尔节以前可是我家的大活动
Yule was a major event in my house.
*传说为圣尼古拉斯的随从 奖励好小孩 惩罚坏小孩*
我们整夜不睡觉 躲坎帕斯
We used to stay up all night hiding from Krampus.
我还记得躲他时唱的歌谣
I still remember the rhyme we'd say to ward him off.
对哦           还记得吧
Oh yeah.    Remember?
对对对对
Yeah, yeah, yeah yeah.
负重之兽，愚人之喜，尤尔之夜放过我
Beast of Burden,fool's delight,spare me on this yuletide night.
当然那时候坎帕斯会先用棍子揍你一顿
Of course back then, Krampus would beat you
然后把你扔进他的背包
with a stick before he threw you in his sack.
我代表Kenzi问下，谁是砍爸死
If I may Kenzi in her absence:who's got cramped-ass?
是坎帕斯
Kram-pus.
就像圣诞老人似的 不过完全相反
He's like your Santa Claus only the complete opposite.
首先他在一年里最热的那天从烟囱爬进你家
For one thing he slides down your chimney on the hottest night of the year.
听起来还真是我喜欢的精灵
Mmm sounds like my kind of elf.
等会，那不会是坎帕斯的尤尔糖果吧
Whoa whoa, are those are Yule candies for Krampus.
你可得在他的坏小孩名单上
You're gonna be on his naughty list.
得了吧，姐全身都写满了坏小孩
Oh bitch,I am the naughty list.
你能反驳吗
Can't argue with that.
不能
Nope.
我好累呀，你开车吧
I am tired,you drive.
天啊，我得赶紧把湿衣服换掉
My god, I gotta get out of these wet clothes.
啊
Agh.
您先请
After you.
嗷
Ow!
本作品片源来自互联网，仅供个人影视制作学习交流之用
任何组织和个人不得公开传播或用于任何商业盈利用途
挪威金毛的胡须最有爱了字幕组  r(st)q
英文字幕：来自互联网
翻译：Neffititi 骷髅头正宫_K 李夹碎
压制：潜行的五
校对、精校：潜行的五
发布：百度贴吧Tamsin后援群
资源下载请关注瓦尔基里字幕组官方微博
S408  Groundhog Fae
尤尔之神 赫尔之子
The Lord of Yule,the Son of Hel
请聆听我们的秘密
to him our secrets we must tell.
否则坎帕斯就……
Lest Krampus...
*Stephanie Meyer 暮光系列作者*
嗷嗷嗷，好了够了，别装琼瑶大妈了
Eugh! Okay,enough Stephanie Meyer.
把你的北欧卷饼拿下来
How about getting off your Kringle
帮我放金箔怎么样
and help me put up some tinsel
谁让你要在夏天过圣诞节
since summer Christmas was your idea?
Yule可是有关悔悟的神圣庆典
Yule is a sacred celebration of contrition
可不是那种捏造出来就为多卖点挖西瓜工具的节日
not some Franken-holiday concocted to sell melon ballers.
*Rudolph 为圣诞老人拉雪橇的八只驯鹿中的领头鹿*
*相传为世界上唯一长着大红鼻子的驯鹿*
你毛衣上还有Rudolph呢!
You have Rudolph on your sweater.
*Eikpyrnir 北欧神话中立于英灵殿顶的雄鹿*
那是Eikpyrnir，是雄鹿！
It's Eikpyrnir,the stag!
它有红鼻子，绝对是Rudolph
He has a Red Nose! It's Rudolph.
欢迎来到圣诞老人作坊
Oh, welcome to Santa's workshop.
你好
Ni hao.
*胡桃夹子 常见圣诞装饰物 通常做成人形 用于夹开坚果*
我亲耐的胡桃夹子们还好吗
How're all my favorite Nutcrackers?
累死了，又是无功而返
Tired. We hit another dead end.
撞上食人魔了
Actually,it was an ogre.
谁知道找个魔法hel鞋这么难啊
Who knew finding a magical hel shoe could be quite so difficult.
看起来很不错哦星星肯
Place looks great K-star.
谢谢
Thanks.
Hale呢
So where's Hale?
谁是Hale
Who's Hale?
我是坎帕斯 快到袋子里来
I'm Krampus.Get in my sack!
*horny也指性趣高涨*
哇，起码也得先请我喝点啥吧，长角怪
Ou...Whoa!Buy a girl a drink first,horny.
看起来真不错
Place looks great!
谢谢
Thanks.
看来你忙得很
Guess you've had your hands full.
姐还可以更忙点
Not as full as they're gonna be.
是吗      恩哼
Ouu.  Ahem.
噢，好吧，大家听好了
Oh,uh okay...people listen up!
Bobo最近压力山大
Bo-bo has been really  stressed out lately
我们要给她减减压
so we want to show her a good time.
*FaLaLaLaLa 著名圣诞颂歌*
所以我不想看到谁懒洋洋的开趴，你们滴明白？
So I don't wanna see any Fa-la-la-la-lazy-ass partying tonight! Got it?
全力以赴 我们滴明白
Full on partying. Got it.
对我们得让Bo知道我们仍然爱她
That's right. We have to show Bo we still love her.
尽管她是黑暗派了
Yes,that even though she's Dark...
还有点流浪者创伤障碍
And suffering from Wanderer PTSD...
但我们还是支持她
That we are here for her.
她不是一个人在战斗
That she is not alone.
对  干杯干杯
-Yup.
-Here,here.
噢不爽，我睡了多久
Oh gross.How long was I out?
他们居然就这样丢下我不管了
I can't believe they just left me ...
我还在自说自话，真好
and I'm talking to myself,perfect.
漂亮！
Yes!
来吧来吧 你是何弃疗 我是老中医
S'up s'up.You got the disease,Choga got the cure.
诊费只收现金
It's cash only
不过对于你
but uh,for you,
Choga可以通融
Choga work something out.
Choga是个毛呀？
What is a Choga?
你怎会不认识Choga呢
Man,how you don't know Choga?
我可是人尽皆知，如假包换哦
I'm side to side,up and down the dial,yo.
时不我待哟，你到底要不要爽一下
So,uh,tick tock,you wanna ride the dragon or what?
你特么说的是人话？
Was any of that English?
恩 你绝对会嗨翻天哟
Mmm...you ain't never had a high so fly girl.
别骚扰这美女了
Let's not bother the nice lady.
嘿 Bo 尤尔节快乐
Hi Bo.Happy Yule.
谢谢你Bruce
Thank you Bruce.
舔腋窝可是半价
Armpits is half-price!
我才刚来就觉得吐过了
And now I'm tasting vomit and I just got here.
Choga可以解决那个
Yeah Choga could work around that.
喂Choga 来让我们舔一下
Oi Choga, give us a lick.
那是和我想的一样的东西吗
Is that what I think it is?
上面写着黑暗档案处转Bo收，是Bo的笔迹
It was addressed to the Dark Archives c/o Bo in Bo's handwriting.
而我不仅没跟她说
And not only did I not tell her about it
还私自拆了
I kind of opened it.
我看出来了
Yeah,I can see that.
可不能给她
We can't give this to her.
你又知道了
Says you.
哇 嗨  嘿
- Whoa, hey!
- Hey!
你们吓得我气都散了
You guys scared the chi out of me.
Dyson的错  对不起
- Dyson's fault.
- Sorry.
这趴怎么回事？大家都在舔Choga？
And what is with this party? Did everyone here lick Choga?
不知道，这你得问Vex，他们一起来的
I don't know,ask Vex,they came together.
谢谢你们把我一个人扔车里 让我又觉得被遗弃了
And thank you for growing my abandonment issues by leaving me alone in the car.
你不是还有两只手吗
At least you have two hands!
我说 我就只有一只 还有14瓶酒要喝
I mean, I've only one and fourteen more of these to drink.
这是我的塑身衣？
Is this my corset?
谁允许你有财产了
You can't own possessions!
Kenzi
Kenzi!
Bo
Bo...
我们接着喝
We're gonna need more booze.
同意
Agreed.
我的Kenzi雷达在震
My Kenzi sense is tingling.
妹子来让哥看看
Damn girl.Let me catch up.
没事，可能有点胀气
Oh no,it's probably just gas.
那也是性感之气
Yeah,sexy gas.
让蜀黍来给你加下油
Daddy's gonna fill your tank.
你说啥
Excuse me?
没什么，下次我会进步点
Ignore that.I'll get it better next time.
Kenzi的门关着
Kenzi's door is locked
没关系，可她从来没和异种在一起过你知道吗
fine,but she's never been with a Fae before, you know?
Hale最好乖乖听话 但怎么说
And Hale better behave himself,but still
她居然都没下来看看我是否还好
can you believe she hasn't even come down to check on me?
噢，说到不体贴
Oh,and speaking of inconsiderate...
我说，Lauren Dyson是全新的流浪者双胞胎吗
hello,Lauren,Dyson the new Wonder Twins?
对吧
Am I right?
要是打不过
If you can't beat 'em...
就融入？
Join 'em?
他们居然都不知道我不见了
I can't even get them to notice I was missing.
再一次的
Again!
尤尔节是面对自己恐惧的最好时候
Yule is the perfect occasion to confront one's fears.
恐惧？我？拜托了
Fears? Me? Please.
好吧，我想我把借口都用光了就是不想回火车上
Okay so, maybe I'm running out of excuses to not get back on that train but...
可我干嘛要告诉你
why am I telling you all this?
你哪位
And who are you?
有时候答案就在我们面前
Sometimes the answers are staring us in the face.
好好笑
Hilarious.
永远要在孤儿院开杀戒
Always kills at the orphanage.
Bo!
你在这？
You're here?!
Tamsin？
Tamsin...?
真是好抱歉
I am so sorry.
你这是在干嘛
What was that for?
木有关系
Doesn't matter.
两秒钟后你就会全忘了
You're not going to remember any of this in two seconds.
*源自希腊语  感叹 赞叹之意*
哦哇
Opa!
特么的怎么回事
What the F...?
漂亮！
Yes!
来吧来吧，你是何弃疗，我是老中医
S'up s'up.You got the disease,Choga got the cure.
说真的
Seriously
你给我灌什么了
what the hell did you slip me?
你懂的，Choga
Man,you know Choga.
我可是人尽皆知，如假包换
I'm side to side, up and down the dial, yo.
时不我待哦哟，你到底要不要爽一下
So tick tock, you wanna ride the dragon or what?
不，不，我们已经这样谈过了
No no,we already did this.
不可能，Choga怎会忘记舌头妹
Naw,Choga never forgets a tongue girl.
别骚扰这美女了Choga
Let's not bother the nice lady, Choga.
嘿，Bo，尤尔节快乐
Hi Bo. Happy Yule.
舔腋窝可是半价
Armpits is half price.
谢谢，Bruce
Thanks...Bruce.
又一次
Again.
你那Valkyrie之吻，到底什么意思？
Your Valkyrie lips! What was that?
你还真记得，真不敢相信我不是一个人在战斗
You actually remember! I'm not alone! I can't believe this.
到底怎么了
What is going on?
三秒种后那个穷丑搓
In about three seconds Fugly over there calls
会叫错那个黑毛的名字
Brunette by the wrong name.
Chirstie，你真性感
You're so hot,Christie.
那不是我的名字
That's not my name.
噢Carrie
Oh,Carrie.
是Jeanette
It's Jeanette.
差得好远
I was way off.
*用来刺激肌肉生长的激素类药物*
类固醇妹再喝两口就要……
Lady Roids makes it about two more sips before…
爆了
Fire in the hole.
妈呀，我站这都能闻到
Oh good god,I can smell that from here.
*相当于bigfoot 类似神农架野人一样的怪物*
她是个大脚怪 估计吃了一百多只猫崽了
She's a Sasquatch.She probably ate like a hundred kittens.
*音同 躲避*
和鸭子
And...duck.
我说了躲避了
I said duck.
*著名电影 内有同一天反复循环的情节*
你今天循环多少次了
How long have you been doing Groundhog Day?
你居然没告诉别人？
And haven't you tried telling anyone?
艾玛，好主意，老娘完全没有思考了一百多次
Like,oh my gosh...I didn't even think about that like a hundred times!
嘿，你，我知道这听起来很神经
Hey you,I know this is gonna sound crazy
但是我们被困在量子悖论中了
but we are stuck in some sort of quantum paradox
同一天晚上不停的循环重复
the same night keeps repeating over and over again.
尤尔节傻瓜
Yule Fools!
傻x不谢，疹子愉快
Thanks asshat, and good luck with that rash.
神马？
What?
你马上就知道了
You'll find out.
不管跟谁说都是一样的反应，一次又一次
No matter who I tell I get the same reaction. Over and over.
什么都没有，直到我俩接吻了
Nothing...Until you and I kissed.
恩
Mmm.
没变呀
Nada.
也就你那么觉得
Speak for yourself.
可能你得亲个和你有瓜葛的人吧
Anyway.Maybe you need to do it with someone you have a connection with.
你跟Lauren和Dyson谈过吗
Have you talked to Lauren or Dyson...
你是说把我丢车上的那帮人吗？把我一个人！
You mean the same people that left me in the car,alone?
我上去过了，他们和Vex都怪怪的
Besides I already went upstairs.They're being weird with Vex.
Kenzi都没来看过我
And Kenzi hasn't even come to check on me.
拜托，那妹子是永恒贡献给Hale了
Please,that girl's stuck from Hale to Eternity.
再说这对他们来说只是个普通趴
Besides,for them it's just party as usual.
他们又没有在循环
They are not stuck in the loop.
说哦哇
Say opa.
什么?
What?
三 二 一
Three-two-one...
哦哇
Opa!
这歌真是特么越听越好听
Cuz this song just gets better and better...
他马上就要长疹子了，全身长满哟
He is getting a rash.Everywhere.
哦对，为这干杯
Oh yeah! We can drink to that.
怎样怎样
S'up s'up.
Bruce Bruce人呢
Bruce. ...Bruce?
你找那个肉山干嘛
Yo, whatchyou calling that meat mountain for?
他又不能给你开处方
He can't fill your prescription!
你知道吗，管他三七二十一
You know what...screw it.
老娘要暂停Hel鞋的事
I am calling time out on hel shoes
还有选了黑暗派，所有一切
on being Dark,all of it.
人人都在找乐子
Everyone here is having fun.
现在该我了，从他开始
Now it is my turn.Starting with him.
对15次循环前我就搞定他了
Oh yeah,I got to him about fifteen repeats ago.
那不就得了 赶紧过尤尔节
Well that settles it.Time to get our Yule on.
太好了
Yeah!
哈哈
Woohoo!
这里？当着所有人的面？
Here? In front of everybody?
他们又不会记得
Oh they won't remember.
再说了，你敢说你从没想过这样？
Besides: tell me this wasn't on your list.
每年的尤尔喝酒游戏开始
To commence the annual Yule drinking game
我们喝酒决定要不要告诉Bo盒子的事，同意么？
We shall drink to decide whether or not we tell Bo about the box.Agreed?
同意
Agreed.
正面
Pros.
好吧，Bo一直觉得诚实很重要
Okay,well Bo is always very big on the truth.
对
True.
反面
Cons.
反面，我们搞不好会看着她飞走再也不回来
Cons: We may lose Bo to the big locomotive in the sky forever.
作为一个通晓Bo的为人，不仅仅是她的罩杯号
Well as somebody who knows Bo beyond her rack size
和内裤线的人……
and underwear line...
艾玛医生得一分
Oo, burn!
我觉得我们最好是留一手
I think that the best course of action is some caution.
尽管我爱她  可她有时候确实就跟
Because although I love her, you know she is sometimes
*指Bo行事冲动莽撞*
瓷器店的性感公牛一样
a very sexy bull in a China shop.
作为一个为救Bo牺牲了自己的爱的人来说
Well as someone who sacrificed his love to save Bo's life...
噢，神啊，无聊得要命哦
Oh,wow god,really boring.
嘿
Hi....
比起无数次向她撒谎的……
rather than lying to her countless times...
哇 恩哼
Wow. Mm-hmm.
太好了
A-mazing!
我说Bo可以搞定她自己的事
Let me just say that I've learned that Bo can handle herself.
插手她的命运可不是什么好主意
And it is never a good idea to get in the way of Bo's destiny.
我该告诉Bo吗
Oh,should I tell Bo
Bo不爱我
Bo doesn't love me ...
来吧赶紧想想这个神秘包裹怎么办
Come on, let's figure out what to do with the mystery package
一次性结束这无聊透顶的三人行
and settle the enigma of the most boring threesome ever once and for all!
你们陈述
Present your cases to me!
我来斟酌
And I shall deliberate!
你什么意见
What do you think?
大概和你的意见相反
I probably think the opposite of whatever you think.
好吧  但你知道我们马上要听Vex了 对吧
Granted. But you realize we're about to listen to Vex. Right?
他现在就像是Bo的宠物
Who is sorts kinda Bo's pet now.
别这样 赶紧来Vex队
C'mon now.Come to Team Vex.
我来裁决谁才是更值得Bo的盒子的那个人
Where yee shall be judged, most worthy of Bo's box.
我们走啊走啊 她去哪了没人知道
Round and round we go where she stops nobody knows.
你走了Kenzi好郁闷
Kenzi was pretty bummed when you left.
只是去找我的同类了
Yeah I just needed to find my kind.
其他Valkyrie
Other Valkyries.
找寻自我，你想问的话
Find myself,if you will.
你找到了吗
Did you?
我要弥补好多东西
I have a lot to amend for.
噢，谁不是呢
Oh,Who doesn't.
尤尔节快乐，Valkyrie
Happy Yule,Valkyrie.
Bo我有些事要和你讲
Bo,there's something I need to talk to you about...
那我可没见过
Well that's new.
绝对不是啥好事
And definitely bad.
哦哇？
Opa?
你妹的
Holy shit.
很好,在一起吧
Good, stick together.
来吧来吧，你是何弃疗，Choga是……
S'up s'up. You got the disease, Choga...
你觉得你妈把你从荷叶上赶出来
You think Mama Choga wanted you
是为了让你成个汗液小贩？
to leave the lilypad to be a sweat peddler? Huh?
你有潜力，还有离墙壁远点
You're better than this! And stay away from the walls!
好了，我找过了，灰发帅哥不见了
Okay,I have looked everywhere.Grey-hair McCutie is gone.
好吧，把他带走的那位和时间循环绝对脱不了干系
Okay, well whatever took him must have something to do with the time shifts.
你觉得和我有关吗
Okay,you think this has something to do with me?
因为一有可怕的事发生多半和我有关
Because everything terrible round here usually has to do with me.
不是，冷静点，Tamsin，行吗
No. Chill. Tamsin, okay?
你来了之后还有谁不见了
Has anyone else gone missing since you've been here?
我不知道，我以为大家喝多了就走了
I don't know. I just thought everyone got drunk and took off.
Bruce
Bruce.
他来过，还帮我赶跑了两栖药贩子
He was here,helping me lift amphibian-arms out of my way.
现在他，他消失了
And now he's...gone.
可是Bruce和伽马射线一样庞大呀
Yeah,but like Bruce is like gamma ray huge!
到底什么玩意儿可以
What or who could of...
把他吸进墙
Suck him into a walls?
得，告诉我你记得的来爬踢前发生的所有事情
Okay,tell me everything you remember before you got to the party.
你不会在心灵旅行的时候惹毛了巫师什么的吧
Did you piss off a wizard or something along your travels?
才没呢，我坐了43号公车，在一个加油站下了站
No,no,I took the 43 bus,got off at the gas station,
买了一盒口香糖，然后就直接来这了，我发誓
I got a pack of gum, and I came straight here. I swear.
我们必须在这东西抓走其他人前制止他
Okay, well we need to stop this thing before it snatches someone else.
好吧 可怎么制止它
Ok,um...How?
我不知道，不过通常这种节奏我都会问
I don't know. Normally in these situations I just ask...
Trick
Trick!
应该很容易找到他 他穿了件丑成马的毛衣
He should be easy to find he's wearing one helluva a sweater.
我第一次见到Bo的时候，我就知道她很特别
First time I saw Bo? I knew she was special.
而且是个麻烦精
And trouble.
坚决同意
No argument here.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
阿门
Amen.
但是如果我没在她左右，给她古老的狼人之气
But if I hadn't been there to give her the old Wolf-Chi-Power
她绝不可能度过一次次难关
She would not have survived those trials.
俺呸
Puh-lease.
所以换句话说，我现在仍然应该对她负责
Hahaha,so in a way ... I'm responsible for her still being here
所以我应该有权选择如何处置她的盒子，这个盒子
so I should choose what to do with her box...the box.
反对
Objection!
不不，给你的努力加一分
Nah.No,a point for trying to win.
给你没注意到我罩罩里的奶奶减一分
But minus a point for not noticing my jubblies in this bra.
我才不会上你当
I'm not playing that game.
我第一次见到Bo的时候，她甚至都搞不清状况
When I first met Bo she didn't even know her hole from an ass in the ground.
她总是像这样，姐是嗜血杀手，拦我者死
She was all like "I'm a killer,get in my wayand I'm gonna kill you"
因为杀手都这么做
"that's what killers do."
没错
That's right.
然后我抑制了她的饥饿
And then I curbed her hunger.
她就变成了“也许我还不错 没那么坏”
And then she was like "maybe I'm okay, I'm not so bad".
还有我爱，所以我觉得我们应该
And I love her also, so I think that we should
把这个盒子丢进古老的火焰里，可否
just throw the box in a big old fire, voil?
医森，太谢谢你了，结了
The Doctor, thank you very much, rests!
啊，bo被神秘的黑雾绑架了
Agh, Bo gets kidnapped by mysterious black smoke
给她自己邮寄了一个不祥的包裹
sends herself an ominous package...
我们在吵什么呢
why are we fighting about this?
我不知道 Dyson
I don't know,Dyson.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
我也是
Neither do I.
你怎么能如此爱一个人然后又
How is it that even you love somebody so much and...
让他们失望
Let them down?
没错
Exactly.
我也不明白
Still working on that one too.
你过来
Come here you.
来嘛，医森  哈
- Camon Doctor.
- Hah.
来个爱的拥抱吧
Hug it out.
都这么久了，就给人家嘛，来，给我一点爱
Been a long time. Give it to me. Give me some love.
给我一点爱爱嘛
Give me some love.
好吧    我天
- Okay.
- Oi...
好了
Okay.
*Kumbaya 一首夏令营和童子军常唱的灵歌*
那组织的这个小型心灵鸡汤聚会的天才有什么报酬
So what does the genius get,you know,who organized this little Kumbaya?
你，手重新装回去，放着我来 现现现在
You...get your hand re-attached.By me.Rrright now.
醉医手术，我来做小护士
Drunking surgery. I'll be the nurse.
喔  喔，感觉有点不妙
- Ou.
- Oo, this is getting kinky...
Oh，Trick，Trick，你不知道我们看见你有多高兴
Oh, Trick. Trick, you have no idea how good it is to see you.
你没证据，不是我干的
You can't prove I did that.
啊，行，真简单
Wow.Okay,easy does it.
我昏过去多久了
How long I been out?
你最后记得什么
What is the last thing you remember?
我在帮Kenzi装饰 然后
I was helping Kenzi with the decorations and the doorbell
门铃一直响 然后有个啥乌啪~
kept ringing, and something about...? Oprah!!!
你好漂亮
You're pretty.
得，你必须听我说
Okay,look you have to listen to me.
这听起来不可思议，但是你必须相信我
This is going to sound outrageous but you must believe me.
当然了，你是我的外淫
Of course. You're my grand-dubus.
我的妖孙女
My succu-daughter.
好吧，我们陷在时间循环里了，时间一直在重复
Okay,we're stuck in some sort of a time loop. Time keeps repeating.
我要喝水，嗯
I need water.Mmm.
而且越来越糟糕了，人们不停地消失
It gets worse.Okay.People are disappearing.
至少有一个我们可以肯定 也许还有更多
One we know of for sure but there could be more.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help...
哦哇！
Opa!!
我希望Kenzi比我幸运
Oh,I hope Kenzi's having better luck than I am.
我的Kenzi雷达在震
My Kenzi sense is tingling.
哥要雷雷你的达达 少女
I'm gonna mingle with your tingle like I'm single, girl.
你说啥
Say what now?
这里闻起来不怎么样
It does not smell amazing in here.
我的kenzi雷达在震
My Kenzi sense is tingling.
我也感觉到了 就像燃烧的欲望
I feel it too, it's like a burning sensation.
哈
Huh?
这些不是我的
These aren't mine.
我的Kenzi雷达在震
My Kenzi sense is tingling.
那其实是我的爱之火车
That's just my love train
将你拉近爱的轨道
pulling into your tunnel of...love.
我勒个去
Dammit!
我愿死去千万次
I would have died a thousand deaths
只为遇见你
just to meet you
而当我终于遇见了你
yet now that I have
我希望能够永生不灭
I want to live forever.
艾玛 Hale
Awww... Hale.
就是这个
That's the one.
就这个
That's the one?
嗯对
Mm-hmm.
好吧，这个，Bo给我的“与异种的第一次藏宝盒”
Okay,um,a little,ya know,first-time-with-a-Fae-box  from Bo.
好，我天，准备充分啊
oh wow that's...prepared
我们有可食用的，不可食用的，脱脂的
We've got edible,non-edible,fat-free
坚硬的，防火的，无花果味儿的
firm,fire-proof,fig flavoured and...
那，如果你不想做的话
Look,if you don't wanna do this.
哦不不，相信我，我想和你做
Oh,no I-I do. Believe me.I do.
Kenzi和Hale，第六十七场
Kenzi and Hale,take sixty-seven.
好了，事不过九，醒醒，Trick，集中精神
Okay,ninth time's the charm,c'mon Trick! Concentrate!
不是我干的，你没证据
You can't prove I did that.
我们现在卡在时间循环里，墙壁还在吃人，救命呀
Okay, we're in a time loop the walls are eating people, help!
哦，这个，不妙
Oh this...this is bad.
什么？是Una Mens那种等级的不妙？
What? Una Mens bad?
还是抽着烟睡着了的不妙？
Smoke-nappers bad?
还是艾玛还有六个周的冬天那种不妙？到底是啥！
Six more weeks of winter bad? What!?
尤尔节傻瓜们
Yule fools!
他根本一点忙都帮不上
He's useless to us.
你好美
You're pretty.
姐知道
I know.
他一直都这么没用
He's been useless.
听着，我想说这个想了很久了
Look,I've been wanting to say this for a while.
我知道你没有帮我找流浪者
I know that you haven't helped me find the Wanderer.
为什么
Why?
因为我很怕
Because I'm terrified.
你有什么还没说
What aren't you telling me?
我不是想催你可是
Okay, I don't mean to rush you but...
哦哇
Opa!
我去 Trick
Oh dammit,Trick.
还有谁知道尤尔节相关的事
Who else knows about Yule.
Hale，大事不妙，我们身处危机了，可能是Una Mens搞的鬼
Hale! Something is going on, we're in danger, it could be Una Mens.
我们试过好多次了，可是没人把我们的话当真
We've tried this already. And nobody is taking us seriously.
不会的，Una Mens还没傻到在尤尔节上捣乱
Nah,Una Mens ain't dumb enough to cause trouble on Yule.
*西方传统，圣诞节槲寄生下人人皆可接吻*
擦，他们没准在槲寄生那儿接吻呢
Hell,they're probably off playing kissyface under the mistletoe.
千万别告诉他们是我说的
Please don't tell them I said that.
不管谁搞的，我们得搞个水落石出，Kenzi呢？
Well whoever it is,we need all hands on deck. Where's Kenzi?
又在洗白白呢，哦哇
Off freshen up. Again. Opa!
彗星，丘比特，闪电一击
Comet,Cupid and Blitzen.
你知道时间循环
You know about the loop?
你还乐在其中？
You're in on it?!
哈哈，坎帕斯也整了你们两个人，他可真牛
Haha,Krampus got both of you too? Oh man,he's got skills.
等等
Hold up.
发生的这些都是傻逼的节日整蛊
This entire thing is just some stupid holiday prank?
真的假的？
Seriously?
坎帕斯干的？
Krampus?
就是我们之前讨论的那个反圣诞异种
You mean that Anti-Claus Fae you guys we're talking about?
对 每年他会选几个尤尔节傻瓜重复这一夜
Yeah, every year he picks a few Yule fools to repeat the night.
完全无害的
It's totally harmless.
无害的
Harmless?
我们刚看见有人被吸进墙里了
We just saw some guy get sucked into the wallpaper.
虾米？不不，坎帕斯以悔恨为食
What? No, no Krampus feeds on regret.
这就是为什么他把人放进时间循环里
That's why he puts people in the loop;
不然不一会他们就深陷麻烦了
sooner or later they'll get into all kinds of trouble.
喂Kieblr，特马的发生什么了
Hey Kiebler, what the hell's going on here?
你居然叫这种场面尤尔节派对，没有水果
You call this a Yule party? No fruit?
*Vanir：是北欧神话中与阿萨神族对立的大支神族，以海洋之神尼奥尔德为首，居住在华纳海姆。*
没有给华纳神族的献祭
No offerings to Vanir?
没有祝酒词
No wassailing.
这货 这货根本就不该出现在这
And this...this has no business here...
那我们现在是要互相狗拿耗子瞎操心了
Oh now we gettin' all up in each other's business?!
这个脏兮兮的狗才不是雄鹿Eikpyrnir
This mangy cur is not Eikpyrnir,the stag.
这是鲁道夫驯鹿！
It's Rudolph!!
我就知道！
I knew it!!
Trick得来评评理
Trick has got to hear this.
小波波，你去哪里了
Bo-bo,where you been?
我去哪儿了
Where have I been?
喂伙计，我开始觉得这个派对并没有邀请你来
Hey, buddy. I'm starting to think that you were not technically invited...
坎帕斯之夜应该是景仰之夜
Krampusnacht is a night that people should revere ...
你亵渎了尤尔大神就要悔恨终日
You'll rue the day that you chose to desecrate the Yule Lord!
Bo小心
Bo,watch out!
美妙的圣诞节啊
Sweet Christmas.
Kenzie
Kenzie?
在楼上和Trick在一起安全点
Upstairs safe with Trick.
那货是，伪劣圣诞老人嘛？他叫个啥？坎帕斯？
Was that...shitty Santa? Whats his name.Krampus?
Krampus不会把人吸到异空间的
Krampus ain't supposed to space suck people.
不，他是那种善良的老捣蛋鬼
No,he-he's just a kindly old prankster who whisks
把调皮的小孩扫进他的袋子里，然后带去糖果乐园
naughty children off in his sack to Candyland.
很明显，今年他的技术升级了
Yeah well apparently he's really stepped up his game this year.
我怎样才能找到他
How do I find him?
我们先想想我们是在哪
Uh,we go back to wherever
进了他的雷达区，大概
we showed up on his radar,I guess.
任何地方都有可能
Which could be anywhere.
好吧，Tamsin下车买了口香糖
Okay,Tamsin stopped to buy gum.
她从43号公车下来
She got off the number 43 bus...
也就是说很靠近
Which goes right by...
加油站
The gas station.
我的神,要是她发生不测了怎么办
Oh god, what if something happens to her?
淡定
Stay calm.
我们总算还有时间，记得不
If we got one thing on our side it's time. Remember?
天啊Hale，你为什么自愿呆在这个循环里
God,Hale why the hell would you put yourself through this voluntarily?
等等，你和，肯子
Wait? You and...Kenzi?
天，这太下三滥了
God,that is just skeevy.
喂喂，和下三滥正好相反好吗
Ow-ow-ow.It's the opposite of skeevy!
看吧  我总算有个机会可以无限完善我的技术
Okay, look I had a chance to perfect my game.
大概就是这意思
So to speak.
我会告诉她的，我发誓
I swear I was going to tell her.
你刚已经告诉她了
I think you just did.
啥
What?
谁是尤尔节傻瓜呀现在
Who's the Yule fool now, hm?
别，等等，让她去吧，过个几分钟她就
No wait, just leave her. In a few minutes she won't remember
不会记得任何事了，对吧
any of this anyway. Right?
也许吧
Maybe.
但那样是不对的
But that doesn't make it right.
哦哇
Opa!
谢谢这个爬梯 我怎么有点痒
Thanks for the part-ay. Why am I itchy?
我这次没有从车子里开始了 发生什么了
I didn't start back in the car. What happened?
我们停止时间循环了吗 搞毛啊
Are we done repeating the loop? What does this mean?
这意味着坎帕斯找到了
It means Krampus has found
某个拥有足够悔恨的人
someone with enough regret to tide him over.
而我们就恢复正常了
And as for us, we're back to normal time.
所以日子照过，只是没有了Tamsin
So life continues,without Tamsin.
噢，我必须去那个加油站
Oh,I've gotta get to that gas station.
你呆在这里保护其他人
You stay here and protect everybody else.
女侠留步
Whoa... Bo.
钢之匕首，骨之柄
Blade of steel,hilt of bone.
尤尔节前夜，你必须要赎罪
Yuletide Eve,you must atone.
听着，坎帕斯也许很好笑，但是并不代表他人畜无害
Look,Krampus may be a joke but that doesn't make him harmless.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我要在那明信片上嘘嘘
I'll pee on the postcard.
得了得了
All right, all right. Whoa, whoa...
这里这里
Here it is,here it is.
你确定你知道你在干嘛
Are you sure you know what you're doing?
没搞错吧你，她就是双手绑着背在后面
Are you kidding me? She could do an emergency brainopsy
也能做脑部肢解
with both hands tied behind her back.
根本就没这种手术 但是谢了
That is not a thing, but thank you.
拜托 你能确认一下这是你的手不
Please, can you please confirm that this is your hand.
人家还要镇静剂
I'm going to need more sedatives.
诶，说真的，我们把Bo这盒子怎么办啊
Hey,honestly《what are we doing with Bo's box?
显然不能给她
Well obviously,we can't give it to her.
哪里显然了
Why obviously?
因为Dyson啊，我说往东你就要往西，要姐发飙
Because Dyson,if I said green,you'd say purple,to get my goat.
我没想要你发膘啊，我想要啥膘都成
I don't want your goat.I can get any goat I want.
哥捞膘一把手...
I'm a good goat-catcher...
你们要的明明就是同一块肥膘好，我们早知道了
Oh, you both want the same goat. We get it already.
你们两个不知道的是
What you two don't get.
其实你们已经不讨厌彼此了
Is that you don't hate each other anymore.
好吧，这东西里面有啥
Okay, what's in this stuff?
一大坨真相...
A whole lotta truth...
还有一点Choga汗液，哇哦
and a little Choga sweat. Woohoo!
我跟你说啊，他说得没错
You know,he's right though.
我早就不讨厌你了
I haven't hated you for a long time.
你是唯一一个懂我困境的人啊，小狼
You're the only one that gets my predicament,Wolfie.
你还这么搞笑
And you make me laugh.
为了我们干杯
To us.
为了Bo
To Bo.
为了醉醺醺的手术~爽！
To drunken surgery.,Gah!
嗯
Ouu mmmm.
别碰老娘 老娘要把那个放你身上
Get away from me.I gotta put that on you.
Tamsin？！
Tamsin?!
Tamsin？
Tamsin?
你在不？
Are you here?
Tamsin？
Tamsin?
哦又回车里了
Oh,and it's back in the car again.
又用圣诞废柴来塞老娘的袜子是吧，傻叉
Come to stuff my stocking with your Yule log again, stud?
太对不起了，小祖宗，那太蠢了
I'm so sorry lil mama,that was stupid.
那我们做了多少次...
So how many times did we...?
没啊，一次都没
No,none.
我发誓一次都没
Not once,I swear.
我是说好几次都是箭在弦上但是就没...
I mean we came close a couple times but we never...
连上？
Connected?
诶我只想让今晚完美些，知道不？
Look I just wanted to make this night perfect, you know?
嘿哥们，我懂你
Look dude, I dig you.
但是说真的，你是异种，我是人类
But be real. You're Fae, I'm human.
永远不会完美的
It's never gonna be perfect.
可我也不想去改变什么
And I wouldn't have it any other way.
我就是不想让你失望
I just didn't want to disappoint you.
你开玩笑啊
Are you kidding me?
*Casanova 18世纪意大利的著名花花公子*
扎莫拉族的情圣公子哥儿？
The Casanova of Clan Zamora?
我还从没这么做过
I've never done this before.
和那些，我真正在乎的人
With someone...I really care about.
诶
Whoa.
哪儿去？
Where are you going?
洗白白
To freshen up.
人人都值得有第二次机会嘛
Everyone deserves a second chance.
不急，我们有的是时间
There's no rush. We have time.
呃
Eugh!
这什么鬼地方啊
What the hell is this place?
Tamsin？
Tamsin?
哦嗨 Bo，你怎么样了？
Oh hey Bo! How you doing?
我得把你从这里弄出去
I'm gonna get you out of here.
不用，没事的
No.It's okay.
我一直都很淘气，但是现在我要变糖了！
I've been naughty but now I'm gonna be candy!!
我已经把机器弄坏一次了
I already broke the machine once.
现在变糖要等着了！
Now I have to wait to be candy!
好吧被洗脑了的小娃娃
Okay,brainwashed Betty.
听好啊：你做坏事了？
Listen up: have you been naughty?
是，可谁没做过啊
Yes,who hasn't?
但是你是个好人
But you are a good person.
而且再怎么说，你可是我朋友
And despite all,you are my friend.
我不会把你这么丢下的！
And I'm not leaving you behind!
要是他们把我做成棒棒糖了
If they make me into a lollipop
我想要你舔第一口
I want you to have the first lick.
好了，够了，我要把你弄出去
Alright,that is it.I'm getting you out of here.
呃
Eugh!
卡得也忒紧了，我得找点东西把这机器弄停
Those are on too tight.I need something to stop the...
嗯，Hale我真想亲你一口
Eugh. Hale I could kiss you.
嗯
Eugh!
好了来吧 走吧
Okay come on, let's go.
哪儿也不准去
You're not going anywhere.
我们干嘛想啊
And why would we want to?
蠢妹子啊，这里是尤尔的肚子
Silly girls.This is the belly of Yule.
是把酸变甜的地方，是把熊孩子变好娃娃的地方
This is where sour becomes sweet.And naughty becomes nice.
不对，这里是淫妖变邪恶圣诞老人
Uh, no this is where the succubus goes bad Santa
狠狠收拾你伪装屁股的地方，因为这些
on your badly camoflage'd ass.Because all this?
都是坏圣诞节
This is just Bad Christmas!
亵渎！
Blasphemer!
根据古老的尤尔法，Valkyrie是我的
The Valkryie is mine by  the ancient laws of Yule.
*圣尼古拉斯传说为圣诞老人的前身 乐善好施*
是吗，根据亲爱的圣尼古拉斯赐予我的力量
Oh,yeah? Well by the powers vested in me by merry old Saint Nick
我说她跟我走
I say she's coming with me.
行啊，你带走试试
Fine. Take her.
你试试
If you can.
来吧
Come on.
好痛
Ou!
Tamsin你得帮我，没有你我做不到
Tamsin I'm going to need your help,I can't do this without you.
可要是我变糖了，就不会再伤害任何人了
But if they make me candy,then I can't hurt anyone anymore.
然后大家都会喜欢我
Then everyone will like me.
我喜欢你啊
I like you...
我把真相都告诉你，你就不会喜欢我了
You won't like me when I confess the truth.
我就是流浪者能找到你的罪魁祸首
I'm the reason the Wanderer found you.
我前生靠抓捕异种逃犯赚钱为生
In a previous life I hunted Fae fugitives for a price.
我是个Valkyrie
I was a Valkyrie.
我最强
I was the best.
也最贪婪
And I was greedy.
和他对视了一眼我就知道
One look into his eyes and I knew
我从未见过真正的邪恶
I'd never really met true evil.
直到那刻之前
Not until then.
我告诉自己我无力拒绝这种野兽
I told myself I was powerless to refuse this beast
所以我收了他的赏金去找一个妹子
so I accepted his bounty to find a woman.
一想到他描述的妹子根本不存在 我就觉得良心稍安
I took comfort that the girl he described couldn't possibly exist.
眼睛既蓝又棕
Eyes both brown and blue.
又贞洁又放荡
Virtuous,yet lustful.
不属黑暗也不属光明
Neither Dark nor Light
却二者兼备
yet both.
看吧
So you see.
你本不该是真的
You weren't supposed to be real.
结果我却帮那野兽找到了你
And the fact that I helped that monster find you...
嘿，Tamsin，听我说
Hey,Tamsin,listen to me.
那些都无所谓了
None of that matters now.
你知道吗
Do you understand?
嘿
Hey
我原谅你了
I forgive you.
怎么，一点都不尊重传统吗？
So,no respect for the old ways?
我们走着瞧
We'll see about that.
兄弟，你真是浓缩的神经病
Buddy, you are ten pounds of crazy in a two pound bag.
承认你吃了它，承认吧
Admit you ate it.,Admit it!
哇等等，这就是为啥你抓我们
Whoa, whoa whoa, that's what this is all about?
因为我们吃了你们加油站的人肉糖果
We're here because we ate your gas station people candy?
人们以前光听到坎帕斯的名字就吓得哆嗦
People used to cower at the mere mention of Krampus.
他们需要提醒
They just need a reminder.
坎帕斯大爷，或者别的啥
Well Krampus, or whatever the hell your name is...
他可不是坎帕斯
He's not Krampus...
我才是
I am!
当当当当
Ta-da. Ta-da.
你妹的二大爷
Holy shit.
先别忙
Hold that thought.
你说了今年我主打
You promised this would be my year!
安静
Silence!
熊孩子真是好有趣，对吧
Children are such a delight, aren't they?
可他们取悦大人的时候也太狂热了点
But they get a little bit more over zealous when they try to please.
到底出了什么问题
Now what seems to be the bother?
恩，问题就是
Uh,the bother
这个Jeffrey要把我朋友变成糖果
is that Jeffrey over here is trying to turn my friends into human gobstoppers.
*Wonka  出自电影《查理与巧克力工厂》 工厂老板名字*
赶紧去旺卡别人吧，老娘这可行不通
So go wonka-fy someone else coz that ain't happening.
Jeffrey 这是真的？
Jeffrey, is this true?
他俩都很不错但是我选的她
They're both worthy offerings but I choose her.
哦，运气真好
Aww...Lucky.
你选了她
You choose her?
啧啧啧，美女们，行行好
Tut-tut-tut,ladies please.
一定要有牺牲的，法律说得很明白
A sacrifice must be made. The laws on this are clear.
是是我知道
Yes,yes I see.
我为我儿子道歉
Again,allow me to apologize for the boy
他还有待历练
he has a little bit of growing to do.
历练，之类的
Growing...nevermind.
你们可以走了
You can go.
还有你
And you.
你也快滚
You too!
我要去告诉妈妈
I'm telling Mom...
你把他们怎么了
What the hell did you do to them?
我把他们放了呀
Oh,I set them free of course.
那为毛我还在这
So why am I still here?
孩子，你内心住的黑暗
There's darkness in you my child
都够做几百年的糖果了，或者还更久点
enough to make candy for centuries maybe even longer.
还有你的罪恶感，你的拒绝
And the guilt. The denial.
复杂的感情是最好的糖果原料
Complex emotions make the best candy.
你，我的小淫妖
You,my little succubus...
我可从来没做过蓝色的糖
I have never made blue candy before.
放开我，我或许会饶你不死
Let me go and I'll consider letting you live.
哈哈，不，还是这样最好
Haha,No,it's better like this.
看，你再也不会伤谁的心了
You see,you won't be breaking any more hearts
再也不会伤害谁
no more hurting anyone.
你将会给每个人都带来甜蜜
You'll just bring sweetness to everyone you meet.
你是在吓唬我吗？
Is that supposed to scare me?
酸变成甜，坏就是好
Sour becomes Sweet. Naughty is Nice.
罪恶感变成胶水，拒绝则是非洲的一条河
Guilt becomes Glue...and Denial is a river in Africa.
我才不怕你
I am not afraid of you!
相信我吧，孩子，我告诉你
Believe me child when I tell you...
只有真相才能让你解脱
only the truth shall set you free.
不敢直面恐惧，又怎能变得纯粹
How can you be pure when you will not confront your fears?
好吧
Okay!
是的 我怕 你就想听这个吗
Yes, I'm scared. Is that what you want to hear?
呵呵
Aha...
我好怕会选择错误
I'm scared of making the wrong choice.
好怕会再一次失去我的朋友，我的家人
Of losing my friends...my family...again.
一想到我会变成什么样我就怕得要死
I'm terrified of what I'll become.
哦
Ooo!
一想到我能干些什么我就怕得要死
I'm terrified of what I'm capable of.
流浪者和他想让我干的事都快把我吓尿了
I'm terrified of the Wanderer and what he'll make me!!
哈哈
Aha!
我很害怕
I'm scared.
真的真的很害怕
Really,really scared.
你不用怕
You don't have to be.
有我在
I've got you.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
我们是不是还……
Are we still...?
没事了
It's okay.
一切都恢复正常了
Everything's back to normal.
至少恢复到这疯狂地方的日常
Or at least what you call normal in this crazy place.
Bruce？
Bruce?
在你床上人事不省中
Passed out in your bed.
小糖果累坏了
Lil' nugget was all tuckered out.
流浪者，你遇到的那个邪恶之人
The Wanderer.That evil that you met.
会是我的父亲吗
Could he be my father?
那东西会为了寻找理想伴侣干出任何事情
That thing would've done anything to claim his ideal mate.
就算是自己的亲生女儿也一样
Even if it meant creating her himself.
Bo，你还好吗
Bo!Are you okay?
我还好，真的
Yeah,I'm fine,really.
你,你个死孩子,麻麻都快担心死了
And you,young lady,you had me worried sick
你知道吗
do you know that?
麻麻对不起
I'm sorry Moms.
我们等会再收拾你
We will deal with you later.
看来你和Hale言和了？
I see you and Hale worked things out.
姐姐 我才不会喝一杯烂酒就啥都说呢
Oh sister please,I never kiss and tell...within earshot.
或者干啥都说！相信我~我们啥都干了~哇~~~
Or do-everything-and-tell-and-trust-me-we-did-everything.Whoa!
这里绝对还有什么酒可喝
There's gotta be something left to drink in this place.
哦，不行，我不想当坏人
Uh, oh no, I feel incredibly bad and I have
我也不知道是怎么回事，但是显然尤尔节
no idea but, it's Yule and apparently...
光明派庆祝尤尔节的地方
The Dark aren't allowed to enter a house where the Light are celebrating Yule.
黑暗派午夜后就不让进了
Not after midnight.
不是异种该干的
It's not the Fae way.
Tamsin
Tamsin.
Lauren跟Vex走了
Lauren left already with Vex.
她将要，1 醒酒
Uh, she had to A: sober up
2 把他的手缝回去
and B: uh, sew his hand back on properly...
说来话长
it's a really long story, but um,
不想进去和那些神经病混，我陪你吧
I'm not going in with those jerks. I'm gonna stay with you.
不用，你回去吧， 真的
No, no please go inside. Really.
我想一个人静静
I need some time to myself.
想点事情
Sort through a few things.
不要，真的，回去吧
No.Honestly, just go.
你非要这样的话，哦对，我找到了个盒子
Well if you're gonna push me... Oh! And I found this box
在床上，Dyson旁边，他醉得一塌糊涂
on the bed next to Dyson,who's like totally passed out.
上面写了你的名字
It has your name on it.